//Direct Field Access
const proxy = document.getElementById("proxy");
const question = document.getElementById("question");
const firstAnswer = document.getElementById("answer0");
const secondAnswer = document.getElementById("answer1");
const thirdAnswer = document.getElementById("answer2");



/**designed to create a personalized welcome message for 
 * a user and then gradually fade out the welcome elements. 
 */

function welcomeUser(){
    const name = document.getElementById("userName").value.trim();     
    if(name ===""){
        alert("Please inter your name :)")
        return;
    };
    document.getElementById("answer0").disabled = false;
    document.getElementById("answer1").disabled = false;
    document.getElementById("answer2").disabled = false;

    const message = `Welcome ${name},  The quiz is short, like summer here ,
      SkÃ¥l!(That's "cheers" with a side of kanelbullar) `;

    const newClass = document.getElementById("welcomeMessage");

    newClass.textContent= message;

    // Use a builtd-in  function to fade the button.
    setTimeout(()=>{
        document.getElementById("btn-message").classList.add("fade");

    }, 500);

    // Use a builtd-in  function to fade the button.

    setTimeout(()=>{
        
        document.getElementById("userName").classList.add('fade-slowly');
        newClass.classList.add('fade-slowly');

    }, 2000);

    // Use a builtd-in faction to remove the whole elements after 4 secornd

    setTimeout(()=>{
        document.getElementById("messageContainer").style.display = "none";

    },4000);

}

// Adds keyboard accessibility for users to submit forms by pressing Enter, providing an alternative to clicking.
document.addEventListener("keydown", event=> {
    if(event.key ==="Enter"){
    welcomeUser();
    }
});


// An array of questions.
const questions = [ 

    {
        "question":"1: We all love IKEA, but which country was it founded in?",
        "answers":['Denmark' ,'Sweden' , 'Norway'] ,
        "correct": 1
    },

    {
        "question":"2: I'm a country often confused for a Scandinavian one, but I don't truly belong. Who am I?",
        "answers":['Denmark' ,'Sweden' , 'Finland'] ,
        "correct": 2
    },

    {
        "question":"3: What is the capital of Norway ?",
        "answers":['Oslo' ,'Helsinki' , 'Copenhagen'] ,
        "correct": 0
    },

    {
        "question":"4: Which Scandinavian capital city is famously spread across numerous islands, all connected to each other ?",
        "answers":['Copenhagen' ,'Stockholm' , 'Oslo'] ,
        "correct": 1
    },

    {
        "question":"5: Which Scandinavian capital city is famously spread across numerous islands, all connected to each other ?",
        "answers":['Copenhagen' ,'Stockholm' , 'Oslo'] ,
        "correct": 1
    },

    {
        "question":"6: which is the largest coffee chain in the  Scandinavian countries. ?",
        "answers":['Costa' ,"Wayne's" ,'Espresso House'] ,
        "correct": 2
    },

    {
        "question":"7: Alright, alright, we get it, you're amazing at recycling, Scandinavia! But which one of you is the best, the absolute king of the compost bin??",
        "answers":['Denmark' ,'Sweden' , 'Norway'] ,
        "correct": 1
    },

    {
        "question":" 8: Which Danish store is basically IKEA, but with a different accent?",
        "answers":['JYSK' ,'MIO' , 'ILVA'] ,
        "correct": 0
    },

    {
        "question":" 9: Mads Mikkelsen, the man who can make even eating a liver look sophisticated (and terrifying!) in Hannibal,but which mysterious land did he emerge from?",
        "answers":['Denmark' ,'Sweden' , 'Norway'] ,
        "correct": 0
    },

    {
        "question":" 10: Its capital is a modern art hub ?",
        "answers":['Denmark' ,'Sweden' , 'Norway'] ,
        "correct": 2
    },
]



let questionNumber = 0;

/**
* Loads a question into the display.
*/
function loadQustion (){

    question.innerText = questions[questionNumber].question;

}

/**
* Loads a Answers into the display.
*/
function loadAnswers () {

    firstAnswer.innerHTML = questions[questionNumber].answers[0];
    secondAnswer.innerText = questions[questionNumber].answers[1];
    thirdAnswer.innerText = questions[questionNumber].answers[2];

}
  
 /**
 * Triggers the functions responsible for loading both questions and answers.
 */
function quizTrigger(){
    let quizLenght= questions.length;
    if(questionNumber < quizLenght) {
        loadQustion();
        loadAnswers();
    } else {
        endTheGame();    
    }

}
    
let correctScoreAmount = 0;
let inCorrectScorAmount = 0;

/**
 * To check the answer given by the user.
 * @param {} selectedAnswer 
 */

function checkAnswer (selectedAnswer){
    correctAnswer = questions[questionNumber].correct;
    if (selectedAnswer === correctAnswer){
        console.log('high five');
        correctScoreAmount ++;
        document.getElementById("correctScore").innerText = correctScoreAmount;

    } else {
        console.log("Sorry, it's not correct");
        inCorrectScorAmount ++
        document.getElementById("inCorrectScore").innerHTML = inCorrectScorAmount;

    }

    // Load the next question.
    questionNumber ++;
    quizTrigger();

}

 
quizTrigger();


/**
 * This function to end the quiz.
 */

function endTheGame () {
    proxy.innerHTML = ` ${correctScoreAmount} out of 10 , That's not a scoreâ€”it's a 
    mystery wrapped in confusion.ðŸŽ‰ Want revenge or just a participation trophy?
    <br>
    <br>
    <button onclick ="window.location.reload()">Try again</button>
    <hr>
    `;

}






